export const chapter = "Chapter - 17: Chittor Fort :A Cradle of Historv";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Which fort in India is known for its captivating history and is a UNESCO World Heritage Site?",
          optionA: "Jaipur Fort",
          optionB: "Chittor Fort",
          optionC: "Agra Fort",
          correctAnswer: "Chittor Fort",
        },
        {
          question: "Chittor Fort is located in which region of India?",
          optionA: "Kashmir",
          optionB: "Mewar (Rajasthan)",
          optionC: "Bengal",
          correctAnswer: "Mewar (Rajasthan)",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Who is believed to have initiated the construction of Chittor Fort?",
          optionA: "Akbar",
          optionB: "Mauryan kings",
          optionC: "Alauddin Khalji",
          correctAnswer: "Mauryan kings",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the significance of the Jal Mahal in Chittor Fort's history?",
          optionA: "It's a place where battles were fought.",
          optionB: "It's where Queen Padmini was imprisoned.",
          optionC: "It's where Khalji saw a mirror image of Queen Padmini.",
          correctAnswer:
            "It's where Khalji saw a mirror image of Queen Padmini.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How did Queen Padmini and her companions deceive Alauddin Khalji?",
          optionA: "They pretended to surrender and then attacked.",
          optionB:
            "They offered him valuable treasures in exchange for safety.",
          optionC: "They sent a Rakhi as a token of friendship.",
          correctAnswer: "They pretended to surrender and then attacked.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What tragic event did Queen Padmini and other women in Chittor Fort choose to avoid?",
          optionA: "Massacre",
          optionB: "Humiliation",
          optionC: "Starvation",
          correctAnswer: "Humiliation",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which historical figure did Rani Karnavati send a Rakhi to for help?",
          optionA: "Rana Sanga",
          optionB: "Bahadur Shah",
          optionC: "Humayun",
          correctAnswer: "Humayun",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the association between Rani Karnavati and the festival of Rakhi?",
          optionA: "She used Rakhi as a military strategy.",
          optionB: "She tied Rakhi to Humayun, seeking help.",
          optionC: "She invented the festival of Rakhi.",
          correctAnswer: "She tied Rakhi to Humayun, seeking help.",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which of the following is a notable monument within Chittor Fort?",
          optionA: "Eiffel Tower",
          optionB: "Vijay Stambh",
          optionC: "Leaning Tower of Pisa",
          correctAnswer: "Vijay Stambh",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How many gates are there in Chittor Fort for ensuring security?",
          optionA: "Four gates",
          optionB: "Six gates",
          optionC: "Seven gates",
          correctAnswer: "Seven gates",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "Chittor Fort is located in the region of _______________.",
          options: ["Mewar (Rajasthan)", "Bengal", "Kashmir"],
          correctAnswer: "Mewar (Rajasthan)",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The first Jauhar at Chittor Fort occurred during the early _______________ century.",
          options: ["fourteenth", "fifteenth", "sixteenth"],
          correctAnswer: "fourteenth",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Queen Padmini, the wife of Ratan Singh, was held in the _______________ during Alauddin Khalji's siege.",
          options: ["palace", "Jal Mahal", "temple"],
          correctAnswer: "Jal Mahal",
        },
        {
          question:
            "To deceive Alauddin Khalji, Queen Padmini and her companions pretended to _______________.",
          options: [
            "offer valuable treasures",
            "surrender and then attacked",
            "send a Rakhi as a token of friendship",
          ],
          correctAnswer: "surrender and then attacked",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Rani Karnavati sent a Rakhi to _______________ for help when her army was weakened.",
          options: ["Rana Sanga", "Bahadur Shah", "Humayun"],
          correctAnswer: "Humayun",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The brave Rani Karnavati motivated her army to fight valiantly but resulted in a complete _______________ for it.",
          options: ["victory", "retreat", "rout"],
          correctAnswer: "rout",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The third Jauhar at Chittor Fort occurred when Akbar, the Mughal ruler, attacked Chittor, which was already weakened by the previous _______________.",
          options: ["Rakhi festival", "Jauhar", "victory"],
          correctAnswer: "Jauhar",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Parma Dhai, a nurse, made a great sacrifice by saving the _______________ during a plot to kill the young princes.",
          options: ["Rajput warriors", "elephants", "young princes"],
          correctAnswer: "young princes",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The _______________ is a marvelous 11-storey building built to celebrate Mewar's victory over Malwa within Chittor Fort.",
          options: ["Eiffel Tower", "Vijay Stambh", "Leaning Tower of Pisa"],
          correctAnswer: "Vijay Stambh",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Chittor Fort has _______________ gates built to ensure security.",
          options: ["four", "six", "seven"],
          correctAnswer: "seven",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "Chittor Fort is a UNESCO World Heritage Site.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The first Jauhar at Chittor Fort occurred in the sixteenth century.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Queen Padmini and her companions surrendered to Alauddin Khalji.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "Rani Karnavati sent a Rakhi to Rana Sanga for help.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The brave Rani Karnavati's army emerged victorious in the battle.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Parma Dhai saved Rajput warriors during a plot to kill the young princes.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Vijay Stambh is a 7-storey building within Chittor Fort.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "Chittor Fort has only four gates for ensuring security.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The third Jauhar at Chittor Fort took place during Akbar's rule.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Queen Padmini was held in a palace during the siege of Chittor Fort.",
          options: ["True", "False"],
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
